Guide to the Project WILD Records, 1974-2014 UA.09.21.0001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Project WILD Records
1974-2014
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Project WILD (Duke University)
UA.09.21.0001
5 Linear Feet
0.02 Gigabytes
Project WILD is a student-led program focused on outdoor activities and running a pre-orientation wilderness experience in the Pisgah National Forest every August. The Project WILD records include handbooks and training manuals for both staff and participants, photographs, evaluations, and other materials.
Biographical / Historical
Project WILD was established in 1974 by a group of students working with the Vice President of Student Affairs, and was inspired by outward bound programs. The program, Wilderness Initiatives for Learning at Duke, was originally a pre-orientation experience for incoming freshmen and eventually offered multiple courses or events throughout the academic year. Project WILD s on outdoor wilderness activities including camping, hiking, rock-climbing, solo camping, and other activities.
The primary Project WILD activity is the pre-orientation trip to the Pisgah National Forest in the Appalachian Mountains of North Carolina, taking place in August for ten days to two weeks.
Access Restrictions
In accordance with the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 as amended, Duke University permits students to inspect their education records and limits the disclosure of personally identifiable information from education records.
Provenance
The Project WILD Records were received by the Duke University Archives as a gift in 2018.
Related Materials
Vice President for Student Affairs records, 1923-[ongoing], Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Collection Overview
The Project WILD Records include handbooks and manuals for both participants and leaders, evaluations of the program, correspondence, photographs, and other materials documenting the program.
Conditions Governing Access
Access copies of electronic records must be requested through the collection guide and accessed in our reading room. Contact Research Services with questions.
Pisgah National Forest (N.C.); Outdoor education; Project WILD (Duke University)
- Course Manuals, 1985, 1990-1995, 1997-2010; 21 folders (Box 1)
- Course Manuals, 2010-2014; 5 folders (Box 2)
- Staff Manuals, 1983, 1995-1997, 2000-2007, 2012-2013, undated; 18 folders (Box 2)
- Brochures, 1980s (Box 2)
- Names and Numbers, 1992, 2005, undated (Box 2)
- PWILD Analysis and Criticism, 1998-1999 (Box 2)
- August Trip, 1994 (Box 2)
- March Trip, 1994 (Box 2)
- Fall Report, 1993 (Box 2)
- House Course Documents, 1994 (Box 2)
- House Course, 1983 (Box 2)
- House Course Readings, 2001 (Box 2)
- NCOBS and Cedar Rock Publications, 1992, undated (Box 3)
- August Directors manual, 2000 (Box 3)
- August Staff Evals, 2000 (Box 3)
  Conditions Governing Access
  RESTRICTED: needs additional screening
- March Staff Evals, 2000 (Box 3)
- August Staff Evals, 1999 (Box 3)
- March Staff Evals, 1999 (Box 3)
- August Staff Evals, 1998 (Box 3)
- March Staff Evals, 1998 (Box 3)
- March Staff Evals, 1997 (Box 3)
- August Staff Evals, 1996 (Box 3)
- August Staff Evals, 1995 (Box 3)
- March Staff Evals, 1995 (Box 3)
- August Participants, 1992 (Box 3)
- Locker Relocation, 1991-1992 (Box 3)
- Pwild History Report, 1986 (Box 3)
- Pwild Memories, 1998 (Box 3)
- Other Wilderness Orientaion Info, 1988-1989, undated (Box 3)
- Meeting Notes, 1996, 1997 (Box 3)
- Pisgah Permits, 1992, 1994 (Box 3)
- August Trip Plan, 1994 (Box 3)
- Grant Proposal, 1989 (Box 3)
- Leadership Tests, undated (Box 3)
- March Documents, 1994 (Box 3)
- August Staff, 2000 (Box 3)
- August Report, 2002 (Box 3)
- Pwild Endowment, 1995 (Box 3)
- Correspondence, 1994, 1995 (Box 3)
- Pwild Status Reports Quarterly, 1996, 1997 (Box 3)
- March Post Mortem, 1993 (Box 3)
- Pwild and DUCEE Beginnings, 1975 (Box 3)
- High Ropes Director's Manual, 1998 (Box 3)
- Minimum Safety High Ropes Staff, 2001 (Box 3)
- Fundraising Initiatives, 2001, 2003 (Box 3)
- August Logistics Director's Manual, 1995 (Box 3)
- Locker DooD Correspondence, 1999 (Box 3)
- Staff Welcome Letters, 1996-2001, undated (Box 3)
- House Course Supplement Material, 2007 (Box 3)
- Staff Training, 1996 (Box 3)
- August Debrief, 2000 (Box 3)
- August Review and Debrief, 1999 (Box 3)
- Team Challenge Course Info, 1999 (Box 3)
- Team Challenge Course Safety Manual, 1999 (Box 3)
- Ropes Course Directors Manual, 1996 (Box 3)
- House Course Climbing Night Resources, undated (Box 3)
- Previous Basecamp Schedules, undated (Box 3)
- Ropes Course Stuff, 1989, 1990, 1991 (Box 3)
- Climbing Day Survey Responses, 2001 (Box 3)
- TCC Ropes Course Notes, 2005 (Box 3)
- TCC Miscellaneous, 1997 (Box 3)
- High Ropes, 2001 (Box 3)
- TCC Safety Manual, 1997 (Box 3)
- House Course Manual, 1985 (Box 3)
- Project WILD Handbook, circa 1993 (Box 3)
- House Course Instructor Manual, 2006 (Box 3)
- August Climbing Handbook, 1994 (Box 3)
- Climbing and Ropes Course Staff Manual, 1995 (Box 3)
- Staff Training Manual August, 1997 (Box 4)
- August Staff Training Manual, 1998 (Box 4)
- House Course Trinity Application, 2005 (Box 4)
- Association for Experiential Education Certificate, 1991 (Box 4)
- Schedules, 1999-2000, undated (Box 4)
- Safety Directors Manual, 1999 (Box 4)
- Rafting Trip, 1996 (Box 4)
- Phoenix House Documents, 1995 (Box 4)
- Outreach, 2000 (Box 4)
- TCC and Fuqua Proposals, 2000 (Box 4)
- August Trip, 1988 (Box 4)
- August Trip, 1989 (Box 4)
- August Staff Manual, 1999 (Box 4)
- March Staff Manual, 1998 (Box 4)
- August Staff Manual, 1998 (Box 4)
- August Staff Training, 1999 (Box 4)
- March Staff Manual, 1999 (Box 4)
- March Training, 1996 (Box 4)
- March Staff Training, 1995 (Box 4)
- March Staff Training, 1994 (Box 4)
- House Course, 1993 (Box 4)
- House Course, 1997 (Box 4)
- Service Experience, 2000 (Box 4)
- March, 1993 (Box 4)
- August Trip, 1996 (Box 4)
- Philosophy, 1977-1999 (Box 4)
- Fundraising Documents, circa 1980s (Box 4)
- House Course, 2002 (Box 4)
- House Course Manual, Directors Copy, 1999 (Box 4)
- House Course Manual, Directors Copy, 1998 (Box 4)
- House Course Participants, 1990s (Box 4)
- PWild Documents, 2016 (Box 4)
- PWild Documents, 2004 (Box 4)
- PWild Documents, 2000 (Box 4)
- PWild Documents, 1999 (Box 4)
- PWild Documents, 1998 (Box 4)
- PWild Documents, 1995 (Box 4)
- PWild Documents, 1992 (Box 4)
- PWild Documents, 1991 (Box 4)
- PWild Documents, 1990 (Box 4)
- PWild Documents, 1989 (Box 4)
- PWild Documents, 1988 (Box 4)
- PWild Documents, 1987 (Box 4)
- PWild Documents, 1986 (Box 4)
- PWild Documents, 1985 (Box 4)
- PWild Documents, 1984 (Box 4)
- PWild Documents, 1983 (Box 4)
- PWild Documents, 1982 (Box 4)
- PWild Documents, 1981 (Box 4)
- PWild Documents, 1976 (Box 4)
- PWild Correspondence, 1975 (Box 4)
- PWild History, 1974 (Box 4)
- Photographs: slides, 4 folders (Box 5)
- Photographic negatives (Box 5)
- Photograph album (Box 5)
- Photographs: snapshots, 5 folders (Box 5)
- Digital photographs, 2000; 48 files; approximately 25 megabytes. (Digital-materials UA09210001-SET-0001, Optical-disc UA09210001-OP-0001 - UA09210001-OP-0002, Box Digital Media Box 10)
  Scope and Contents
  Digital photographs in JPEG format.